someone who's really taken the concept
of liquidity to new levels, has gotten
hundreds of thousands in terms of payouts and
millions in terms of funding with prop firms.
You want to understand these things because these
retail concepts are all used to build liquidity
in the market. Not every high and every low has
liquidity. Of course, you need to understand this
is a very common mistake and it can be fixed
with one strict rule. Literally, Marco Trades
is the trader you've never heard of. Up until
now, he has kept his liquidity concept secret
and well-guarded. Liquidity is is everything for
me. It gives me my direction. It gives me my bias,
my entries, A to Z. Basically, he has mastered the
super simple but specific strategy that identifies
market traps that most traders are getting stopped
out on. You have to understand a lot of people
ask me like then why don't I trade these retail
concepts if they somewhat work? They temporarily
work. They they work for good reason purposely
to for the first time ever he is showcasing this
strategy for the world to see on chart fanatics
step by step but also he is using and trading
the strategy live in live market conditions. All
right guys wow high's taken. Let's close out here
and look at that move that puts us at across
four accounts on this special episode on chart
fanatics. Welcome everyone back to Chart Fanatics,
the go-to channel for all your best trading
strategies with the best traders in the world.
And today we are in Miami. We're here shooting
some incredible episodes with incredible traders
and kicking it off with day one. It is a very
good friend of mine, someone who has really taken
the concept of liquidity to new levels and really
opened up so many traders eyes. I would say quite
a unique style of trading, one that I would class
as simplistic. has gotten hundreds of thousands in
terms of payouts and millions in terms of funding
uh with prop firms with traders from all over. So,
it is a strategy that people really really love
and really want to know. Everyone talks about
time, everyone talks about price, but again,
they're missing the one key ingredient, which is
liquidity. So, we're about to go into a deep dive
with the one and only Marco Acetony. Did I say
that right? Aony should add an accent on there.
to you, man. It's an absolute pleasure. Thank you
for doing that. I know you literally just jumped
off a flight and I've thrown you in the deep end,
but where should we begin? Ah, okay. Well, I feel
like the the part of training that everybody
struggles with the most is is direction in my
opinion. Um, I've taught and trained uh plenty of
traders in the over the last couple years and the
the most common trait I see is again it's a lack
of understanding the the current direction or the
current bias in the market right so um for myself
liquidity is is everything for me meaning it gives
me my direction it gives me my bias my entries
right all the way down to that like from A to Z
basically. So, if I can dive into this whiteboard
real quick to give you a little rough breakdown
of what how I view liquidity, how I determine my
bias, all these different things. So, if we have
the market trending to the downside, simple stuff,
we have high, low, high, and we continue selling
off to the downside, right? This high respected
previous highs. So, this might sound very simple,
but yet everyone they over complicate things.
So, high, respected, high, simple things. there's
now liquidity above this high. So, we have to use
this to our advantage. Meaning, if I want to start
looking for buys, easy target right here, right?
So, obviously, there's a lot more components
that's involved. But the most important thing
you have to be able to understand is not every
high and every low has liquidity. Of course,
you need to understand once retail is induced,
meaning sellers are entering right here, it moves
away. Now, there's liquidity above this high. So,
in terms of liquidity, how would you define that?
If you were to define liquidity, just for those
at home who may not understand that side, like
how would you go about defining liquidity? Yeah,
I mean, I feel like a lot of people like to go
really um deep with it. Um and then then like
I said before, I like over complicate things. Um
in my opinion, liquidity is just resting orders in
the market, right? And it's as simple as as simple
as that. So let's just say stop orders. Um usually
the most um the best example for myself, what I
use the most would just again be stop losses. So
if I understand certain traders are entering at
a high or a low then I'll understand that there's
going to be resting liquidity there. So it's
essentially just understanding where those orders
sit in the market. Um so as you that example you
just drew out there. Yeah, exactly. If I can just
give you another one right here real quick. Simple
things like and on the uptrend. So since price
takes out this high over here, this now tells me
the intention behind this move from A to B is now
induced buyers into the market. Meaning they may
think there's momentum, right? or they they're
going to mark this as taking a previous high as
like a BOS in the market. Um so once price returns
back to this area at the extreme, however they
want to look at as support, Fibonacci, um even
smart money concepts, they're going to want to
buy down here. And once the market moves away,
simple things again. Now I know there's liquidity
below this low. So from here, if we were to break
it down, we're looking at what most will be seeing
as say a breaker structure. Exactly. Their boss,
their market OB could be fair value gap here.
could be Fibonacci levels. It could be all of
those together. So here in this example, they
may take the trade here and it might even work
out. It might even work out in their favor. But
so what are you looking at then? As you said,
this is now resting liquidity. You're looking at
this what for entry target. So I need to see this
this whole picture occur. Um and I feel that's
where people may struggle with the most when they
start looking to trade. um how I trade meaning you
have to be patient you have to sit on your hands
you have to allow the liquidity to build sorry
you have to allow the market to build liquidity
so again in this example again you have this high
again getting taken out so as you marked BOS price
returns down to this OB and moves away simple
things like let's not over complicate it there's
now liquidity resting below this low period so
if I'm now going to frame out a whole sell entry
I would look to target this low right and if I
want to look to enter a buy position I'll simply
need to wait for price to trade below the lows. So
now we're below the lows down here. You can look
for your buys back up. Hey guys, I hope you're
enjoying this episode so far. And don't forget,
we send every single strategy breakdown from
every episode for free on chartanatics.com. So
the link for that is in the description below. So
just make sure you click that. You just put your
email in and every single week we will send you an
up-to-date PDF strategy breakdown for you to keep,
to learn from, to reference for free. And don't
forget, we're also launching Chart Fanatics Live,
where your favorite traders from Chart Fanatics
will be live trading every single day. I will
also be including special guests on the live Chart
fanatics edition. So, make sure you go subscribe
to that YouTube channel right now. It's linked on
the main profile of Chart Fanatics. So, make sure
you're ready for that. But, let's get into this
episode. So in this scenario then this is where
I think it really gets interesting because one
obviously requires patience as you mentioned but
this is where it gets interesting because when
most people see this then get broken here that's
then a breaker structure. Exactly. Right. So then
therefore they're then looking for the opposite
what we drew out here. They're looking at the OB
here. They're looking at the fair value gap here.
They're looking at reasons to sell. Exactly.
So why are they going about that wrong? like
what is it that is allowing this to take place?
Cuz a lot would then call that just a standard
fake out or shake out or whatever it may be or
stop-loss hunt, right? Yeah. Which most people,
regardless of whether they label it that way or
not, they're still not capitalizing, you know,
in terms of actually being able to identify,
okay, when is that happening? How do I take a
trade? 100% 100%. And I'll I'll clear this up so
I can give you a a good explanation to this. So,
just like we were drawing before, I'll draw
quickly understanding. So simple just like how we
talked about the beginning um with the highs this
is the same same thing we have a BOS to the upside
meaning market induces buyers here by taking out
this high here we turn we return back to the low
respect the low okay and move away to the upside.
So now again I understand now there's resting
liquidity below the below these lows. Now just
because we've left liquidity here does not mean
right away we're going to run for it. That's just
not how the market market operates. What I tend
to look for now is if we have a high left on the
left hand side over here and this is an area that
sellers are looking to take entries from. Whether
that's going to be like an order blocks we'll
write down like an OB or like a POI. Okay. So,
this is an area that sellers are looking to take
entries from. Again, I I I you want to understand
these things because um these retail concepts are
all used to build liquidity in the market, right?
You have to understand a lot of people ask me like
then why don't I trade these retail concepts if
they somewhat work? You you have to understand
that they temporarily work. They they work for
good reason purposely to induce liquidity into
the market. Right? If these concepts never
worked, smart money, support, resistance,
then why would people trade them? Yeah. Right.
So again, sellers are looking to take entries
up here. the market moves down to the downside
and maybe sometimes what tends to happen as well
is since we're now trading back at this low and we
understand structure traders um retail traders any
any sort of um trader looking to go long they're
going to look to enter in this area so in here so
sometimes what occurs is a reaction up okay again
understand that buyers are looking to take entries
at this low the market gives a pullback and then
sometimes what I can do is I can I manage to catch
a sell entry up here and I can ride it down into
the liquidity right Um but if I all this does at
this point is it it just builds more right just
builds more liquidity exactly and per my concept
per my system I understand that there if there
is reactions in this blue box in this area here
I understand it to be false and it's going to be
shortlived it's just to induce buyers to build
liquidity at the lows I will never trade um I will
never look to take longs above the lows only below
so again in this example here if now I want to
look to take buys back up I will have to look
for buys below these lows. Okay. And then now this
is simple liquidity stuff, right? Buy below lows,
sell above highs. All right. Now, what we were
talking about before is sometimes now if I can
use your red marker, I'll mark on uh so smart
money concept or structure traders will look at
this as like a BOS, right? So I can mark that on
there. BOS. Perfect. Um now the market, what tends
to happen is as we trade back up to the upside,
it'll create some sort of internal lows. Then
finally when we approach these areas again false
reactions. Exactly. So I understand that since
we have taken out these lows 1 2 3 retail looks at
that as a momentum shift. So they're again they're
looking to sell up here. Perfect. So I understand
that the market tends to come up and respect these
areas again to induce sellers to build liquidity
above these highs. If the reaction comes around,
perfect. I'm looking to take a buy entry right
here and then all the way back up into the highs,
right? So, it's rinse and repeat. I have to make
sure I'm always targeting liquidity and taking an
entry after liquidity is taken, right? Cuz a lot
of people make the mistake of yes, you're looking
for a buy below these lows, but what liquidity
are you targeting? Right? There needs to be that
logic that uh yeah, there needs to be that logic
involved for sure. This is really actually in a
way showcasing the fractal nature of of this model
and this way of thinking because this essentially
would be your bigger picture bigger picture in
this case we could say I don't know 4 hour or 1
hour let's say and then this so the actual trading
side of that um you know this liquidity being
swept to then target is actually then say your
15minut happening here with your reactions etc
for sure for example I agree with you but again it
could be you know daily and 4 hours 100% the thing
is this whole scenario I've drawn on um I'm never
trying to pit Like when I draw diagrams like this,
I don't want it to for people to view it as like
a pattern, right? That's not this is just strictly
for understanding because I don't want you guys
to start just print out this diagram, go to your
chart and just try to find this exact scenario
cuz it won't won't work like that. You need to
understand what I'm trying to draw out here and
then obviously put that onto your own chart.
Exactly. For sure. And like you mentioned before,
it's fractal, right? So this could happen on the
daily. It could happen all the way down to the
one minute, right? What are your thoughts in terms
of identifying liquidity? because we've mentioned
in terms of this low or this high, right? Or this
high, sorry. Um, and more so it's because we've
had a potential structural structure made. The
low then being the liquidity of that structure.
Is that how exactly how you're identifying it?
Is there other areas that you would identify as
well? Yeah. So again, this is bringing it back
to the beginning. Um, when I'm talking about I
don't want to ever over complicate anything. A
lot of people would like to look at this as okay,
trend line, channel, whatever it is. But if you
literally just understand this drawing right
here, this part of the drawing right here, it's
literally just this. That's it. So high taken, low
respected, move away. So people can say channel,
people can say trend line liquidity. At the end
of the day, keep it simple and it's literally just
liquidity period, right? Um again, you can you can
look at it as a Fibonacci retracement level, smart
money concepts. I understand that if I see the
market respect a high from A to B and move away,
that tells me there's liquidity above that high.
Mhm. Right. A lot of people like to say, okay, so
this high is taken out. Um, which now I can look
for sells. But why was there liquidity above that
high? Right. Most likely not because it didn't
respect it. Now we have we were now approached
the low down here. If we respect it and move away,
perfect. Simple stuff. There's liquidity below
that low. So this is really identifying where the
resting liquidity is rather than saying that okay
let me keep trying to predict where liquidity
could be formed is actually saying okay where is
it currently. Yeah. So this again this is bringing
back to my point um we were talking about earlier
is the hard part um not necessarily the hard part
the people but the part a lot of people struggle
with is the patience side of it meaning you need
to wait for liquidity to get built right if there
is no liquidity on the chart how am I supposed
to build a direction how much to build a bias
right so that's where people struggle with the
most in my opinion is just sitting on the hands
and waiting for that liquidity to build once
it's built in front of you being able to build
a direction and bias in the market it becomes 10
times easier, right? Um, sometimes you see a big
move in the market occur, right? And like let's
say this is on like the hourly or the 4 hour. Most
likely I'm not trading this current chart for the
next couple days. Why? Because this big move has
just occurred and that means it maybe you can go
into the 1 minute and the 5 minute and and try and
find an entry. But on the current picture right
here on the 1 hour and 4 hour, all I can mark on
is we've taken out this high period. I don't see
any other liquidity. So why would I be trading? M
so as an example of this for example uh we look at
Euro there's actually an interesting conversation
we had cuz this move happened this right here um
we're talking in February time right February of
2025 so we're currently in April towards the end
of April so this has happened you can go back on
the chart and see this and maybe we can actually
pull it up actually later we had a move exactly
like this and I was actually looking at Euro
personally to try and get to that sort of 50% that
balance out the range Right. But before that, all
you had was this, right? And we were here and I
was like, "Okay, this is where I want us to get to
me personally." And I remember you saying how this
is really all you can see price taking up because
below that point, there's no liquidity. There's no
significant even on the lower time frames, there
weren't really any highs and lows. You know, maybe
if you go to the one minute, you'll see obviously
something, but on any other really significant
time frame, it was all just one direction. And
that's where I think that term liquidity void
comes in when we're talking fair value gaps and
POIs etc. Like there's one term liquidity void
and I like it because of that simple fact that
that's what it's really showcasing is there's a
a void a gap a misapity where it's just been one
directional and then what ended up happening and
we'll pull this up on euro later so you can see it
is price did come down and that was great but we
swept liquidity new highs after that. Exactly. And
and then just like you marked out here, if we're
now taking out this low over here, sellers are
going to be looking to take entries where? Below
this high, right? And that's going to be what I'm
going to be viewing as what's called a trap. Yeah.
And probably what happens is, and we'll check the
chart, is we probably had a reaction. Exactly.
And then continue up. Exactly. And there's that
continuation that comes through. And then again,
you know, one of the positives that we definitely
highlighted here is because what happens to people
is when they're in this moment, right? And we've
seen this over these last few, I'd say, a couple
months now, is when this happens, everyone gets
confused. Everyone gets really confused. They're
kind of lost. A lot of the time they're chasing
the sell because they missed the buy. Exactly.
Even though they want to buy overall, right? They
understand it's bullish, but overall they're like,
"Okay, let me focus on selling because of course
we can't just keep going higher." Exactly. The
market can do anything. Exactly. But with this
scenario with liquidity as a focus point of a
strategy and even if let's say it's not a focus
point of your strategy because there'll be people
listening who love the idea of this but maybe they
don't want to fully adapt which is absolutely fine
but by understanding this concept it really opens
your eyes to the markets I would say takes away a
lot of that stress a lot of that sort of unknown
because you just know I just need to wait a few
days let liquidity build up identify it and then
then could be a case we sit on your hand still
like in this case where we're starting to identify
these significant highs and lows now being formed.
We know cuz if you're trading from here you know
you can target this low that's great. If however
you don't feel comfortable that's fine. You just
know that if this low gets taken then you have the
then you have the opportunity to buy. Exactly. And
again that's where the hardest part is. If I can
mark this out this move from A to B from low to
high this is where a lot of traders screw up. They
can't wait for this this move to happen again
from A to B. But once you if you learn how to
um sit on your hands, stay patient, wait for
this essentially this false move to occur,
um you'll avoid a lot of losses, right? Because
I've also taught a lot of people where they'll
be like, "Okay, cool. We have a liquidity at the
lows here. Let me try and sell into it." But the
problem is with that is if we're heavily bullish,
then the price can just continuously leave lows to
the downside, right? So the highest probability
way of looking at this scenario right here is to
wait again for this to form, this high to low,
this trap move to the downside. And then again,
you have the opportunity of riding this back up to
the highs. Let's take a break for a minute there,
guys, because I want to tell you about our
preferred prop firm here at Chart Fanatics,
and it is Apex Trader Funding. We are no stranger
to Apex. We've had Jadecap and Trader Kane on
Words of Wisdom and here on Chart Fanatics.
Now, they are well known for having record
payouts on Apex of over $2 million a piece. Now,
even if you don't achieve a seven figure payout,
the reality of achieving a multi6igure payouts
with Apex is absolutely achievable. and an
incredible opportunity at that. And you can
see that on screen right now with all the
incredible payouts being paid out to traders
around the world, traders just like you. Now,
Apex is the biggest futures firm in the entire
industry and have paid out over $500 million to
traders across the world. No matter the type of
trader, you can be one of them, too. Now, one of
our favorite things about Apex is that you can get
up to $6 million in funding using the 20 accounts
that you're allowed to have and the 300K account
at that that totals $6 million. And another thing
that we love about Apex is that there's no
daily draw down. It's a one-step evaluation
and the fact that is uncapped payouts and 90%
of the profits made are yours to keep. Now,
don't forget, regardless of the type of trader
that you are, you do not have to worry about
trading news as long as you are following your
day-to-day trading strategy. The possibilities
are limitless at Apex Trader Funding. Now, you can
get up to 90% off, 90% off, the biggest discount
in the entire industry at Apex using the code CF
and the link in the description below. Thanks to
them and thanks to Chart Fanatics. Make sure you
get your futures funding with Apex. Now, let's
get back to the episode. Is there any thing we can
draw out just to highlight the fractal nature? So,
you know, let's say we have someone who's a day
trader or scalper, right? But how how it can be
helpful still to understand the bigger picture say
like a daily or weekly time frame even though it's
so far out what that might look like. Let's say
as an example now just to help you you sort of
visualize say you know weekly like this or dailies
like this and this is your liquidity but on the
shorter term time frame um you know you have
something else that you could then target here
for sure I I definitely Yeah. Yeah. 100%. I I can
draw something out for you guys. Um okay cool. So
again it all comes down to liquidity. So maybe
do one side on like the higher time from this
side and lower. Perfect. Perfect. Yeah. So I'll
draw this out just like we've been talking about.
High taken out, low iss respected and we move away
again. We move away from low to high. That's the
important part. So we have liquidity at this low,
right? Perfect. Now if I was to let's do it like
this. So price comes back down to this low. And
now I'm going to draw the lower time frames. So
let's just say in this scenario here, we're
looking at H1, okay? Or even M15, whatever,
whatever you want to use as like a scalper or
intraday trader. H1 H1 I'm using my left hand.
Okay. Um so we sell off from this high. So from
up here we move to the downside. Okay. And we
have liquidity down here. So we come down to the
downside and let's just say we get some highs and
lows printed on and we come we approach low. So
now look how price is approaching these lows down
here. We're approaching the lows. All of a sudden
you get that move up to the downside. So this is
what I was just talking about. Um on your Yeah.
Oh sorry. Yes. to the upside. Um, this is what
we're just talking about that euro example. This
is where a lot of traders, if I can use this green
market, this is where they make the mistake. They
can't wait for this to occur. Okay? But if you
learn to wait for this to occur, this false move
to the upside, then you can now understand that
we have just taken out sellers. Mhm. Right. So, we
trapped sellers, meaning look again, same thing.
High respected high respected high moved away to
the downside. So, there's liquidity above that
high. Simple stuff, right? And then from here
we get a false run to the upside. We take out
that seller liquidity and then that move occurs.
Right? So it's just basically like this boom and
boom. So this would be the sell opportunity
on the lower time frames using the higher
time frames to aid that. And just to showcase
really cuz in this case we're understanding
what's happening between buyers and sellers. On
this side obviously we're showing a higher time
frame but in in essence what could be happening
is that that could be a fair value gap there right
which sits above these highs. And the only reason
I'm highlighting this is that with this method,
there's nothing wrong with it. What works works
or whatever resonates with you is very important.
What I find with this side when it comes to say
SMC, ICT concepts or just generally as well like
retail concepts is a lot of complexities and a lot
still of like unknown, right? For sure. You Yes,
I would say I would argue that ICT concept SMC do
try and tell a story. M but one thing I've always
found with this style where you're really focused
on one thing which is liquidity it tells all of
that story but just in a much clearer fashion in
my opinion right cuz I know that you transitioned
from more that SMC style and then once you really
decided to focus on liquidity and it spent time
as well I know you put in countless chart time to
really develop and build your eye for this um and
I think that's something that can't be avoided
right I think you have to but one thing I just
want to ask about this here is as You said like a
lot of people are too impatient for this move of
course but equally would you say two things that
can be very strong reality for people and what
would you say but is this something that you sort
of face and if so like what did you do is like
you're looking to long anyway right Mhm. but you
see price start to move before and you start to
assume it's going to go without me let me jump in.
Mhm. Right. Right? So you jump in here, let's say
price then takes out that high. It comes back down
and now you're seeing those profits come back down
as well, but you think still, you know, bullish
and then you kind of start to forget your original
plan and you start to buy in some more here
thinking, okay, let me get in better price and
then it continues down and then and then you're
stopped out, right? So this is a very again a a
common mistake and it can be fixed with one strict
rule literally this use the red marker for this.
Um, a strict rule for myself is if we ever are
moving to the downside like like this and I'm
looking for a whole buy scenario to play out, if
we get a move to the upside and we take out highs,
I will not buy this asset pair, whatever
I'm trading until this low is taken out
right here. So, it doesn't matter what happens
anywhere between. Sometimes what occurs is the
market will come down to the downside and then
just go long. It doesn't matter. This is not a
move I was supposed to be in. Okay. Exactly. It's
a very strict rule. Literally, if the market does
not run this low, I will not involve myself. Same
thing. Um, when going to the uh downside um if we
are moving to the uh to the upside like this and
market comes down, I will not look to take a sell
until this high right here is taken out. Right?
So, boom, boom, boom. Now, I can look to sell.
And do you find that if this happens, let's say
this scenario where it does go without you and it
hasn't really met your model yet eventually, would
you say from from memory or experience that this
does end up getting taken out eventually anyway?
That was just going to be my to my next uh topic
I want to talk about this is now going to be a
future target. So this type of price action we
just drew out typically occurs. Let's draw it
again. Exactly. Yeah, let's talk about it. So
market sells off like this, reacts to an area on
the left hand side, we get a move up, right? Um,
again, I'm not looking to take an entry until this
low is taken. Okay. And again, what what happens
sometimes is the market will just do this, respect
the low, and move away. This whole scenario,
this um Yeah, this whole scenario right in front
of us typically occurs maybe if there is news on
a Wednesday, this could occur on like Tuesday.
M why? It's just built liquidity for news the
following day. So yes, almost always I can I can
tell you guys that if we have left liquidity like
this, it's going to be either a future target you
can sell into or another buy opportunity somewhere
down the line. Maybe it's the next day or even the
next week we end up running these lows and then
you can look for that buy back up. So it's just
accepting like with pretty much every strategy
that there's going to be trades that don't play
out. There's going to be trades that you have to
wait for. Y um which is always interesting,
right? Cuz I see why it's so easy to sort of
get drawn into the market. Of course, because you
plan a trade and you sit there and plan and wait,
but then in, you know, at the end of the day, it
doesn't play out for you exactly exactly how you
want it. That's just the reality of these
markets. It cannot be avoided. In terms of
uh internal external liquidity, I guess that's
kind of what we just talked about from the higher
time frame perspective to lower time frame. Is
there any sort of nuance or any sort of things
that you focus on though when comparing the two
external and internal? Yeah. Meaning so like you
got the outside of the range versus the inside. As
I said like we kind of went over it because a lot
of the time the outside is the higher time frame
areas and then the inside is normally lower time
frame. Is there anything that stands out to you as
like more high probable or something you focus on
at all between those two? Not comparing the two
but if there's anything that usually usually um
and we again we'll use a diagram as an example.
markets left liquidity at the highs for me. Um,
if I'm looking for a buy opportunity in this
scenario right here, understand there's liquidity
at this high, I want to target it. Um, typically
what happens is it's now, this is known as your
external, right? The top of the range. Here you
have your bottom of the range. And on the way up,
price will usually, not all the time, but forms
some sort of internal. Okay? Usually, I'm taking
entries off internal liquidity gain taken. So if
we get that false reaction down here, I'm taking
an entry down here and I'm targeting external.
So that that's how I use it. Um and then if I'm
looking for sometimes after this high gets taken
out. Again, it all depends what the higher time
frame is saying. Typically once external is taken,
there's reversals that occur, right? And then
you'll have the sell-off. Why? Because there's
liquidity built here, right? So usually again
reversals occur once external is taken out. I'm
taking entries from internal targeting external.
Yeah, that's the main focus. Yeah. In terms of
uh execution then so how are you going about like
what is your mindset behind sort of the execution
process? So once that's happened this model we
just looked at um you know how are you looking to
execute off the back of that? One simple way I use
for entries is I need to understand which highs
and lows don't have liquidity yet. Basically,
meaning if we have swept out this high, okay,
and moved to the downside, why would there
be any liquidity above this high right here?
There wouldn't be, right? All we've now done is
literally just ran this high to the upside. Price
has not approached the high and moved away yet.
Meaning there there shouldn't be any any liquidity
above this high. Obviously, nothing's 100%. But
this is just a simple concept I apply to my model.
Me understanding that liquidity has been taken out
here. And that's saying basically, let's say,
you know, directly to the left, there's nothing
there either. Exactly. Yeah. It could be like
years ago. Yes. Yeah. But that's not as not as
important. Uh but really this is saying that we've
just reached this high. To the left is down here,
right? Yes. And and let's just say I'm looking to
take some sort of sell entry. I need to see this
this occur. I need to see some sort of liquidity
taken out. Okay. This high print and we move away.
meaning there should not be any liquidity above
this high which means I'm looking to take entries
in here somewhere. Okay, sell entries up here and
I'm I'm targeting whatever sort of liquidity we
have to the downside. Okay, but again I keep it
as simple as possible. I'm looking to take sells
at highs I'm analyzing at as uh no liquidity above
them. Mhm. And but how do you do about executing
them? So in terms of like what do you see um
when it comes to execution? Do you have like
one execution model? or do you have like multiple
or how does that look in terms of so if we were
to take this area here so you've had the reaction
what are you then looking for um with within when
within this high right here. Yeah. Okay. So how
do you how would you go about executing your same
thing I'd want to see. So we're we're tapping
into there in the left hand side. Mhm. We move
away. We build liquidity. I'm taking the sell up
here again off this area up here and target to
the downside. So the same thing I need to see the
buildup occur. This whole scenario play out. Same
thing that's happening on the higher time frames
is happening on the lower time frames. So would
you just execute once the high is taken or exactly
once the high this high is taken. Exactly. That's
why I'm taking a sell entry and I'm always going
to be covering the high I have to the left hand
side. So in this example here if I'm just taking
a direct entry off here stop loss above that high.
Okay. So in this case, stop loss would be above
this high. Exactly. Your execution would come off
the a more fractal sort of confirmation of using
the same mindset, same model. Yep. Understanding
your bigger picture as well. So then you know
where you're targeting already and then from
there you're executing once the high's taken,
stop loss above. Yes. And and obviously again
this is where people make mistakes. We're not
pattern. Well, I'm not a pattern trader. So I
need to make sure there's logic. I need to make
sure I'm targeting liquidity, right? Not just a
random low to the downside. I need to understand
that if there's liquidity to the downside, that's
going to be my target. I love that. So, like we
talked about execution there in terms and stop
loss placement. Like what about in terms of your
management of trades? Are you looking to uh leave
them to run sort of leave just you know set your
trade and then forget it or how you going break
even? You taking partials like what does that look
like? Cool. I'll just use the same diagram. This
is as easy as possible to always go through. So
liquidity left at the highs again buy scenario
for myself. I understand look internal has been
built for myself to use as an entry. Okay. Market
comes up to the upside respects the highs. Okay.
So now I'm looking to take my buy down here. So as
for trade management again in this scenario stop
loss below this low stop loss would be down here
and obviously I'm going to be looking to target
the highs. Something I don't do too often um is
take partials. I'm not the biggest fan of taking
partials. So in this specific scenario right now
if I'm looking to take entries down here once
price sometimes we get a reaction up maybe once
move down further that's fine and then we start
moving to the upside once I start getting this
move up I'll look to trail my stop below this low
essentially what I'm predicting is this low should
not be revisit revisited okay so it's going to
be left for the future um so again I'll trail my
stop below this low so now essentially I've cut my
risk almost in half from this original stop-loss
placement I roll it below here and I let the trade
do its thing I'm not the biggest fan of um setting
my trade to break even unless I've partialed or
like closed majority out and then sure I'll let
it ride be and I'll hold to further targets. So
again, I'll roll my stop right here. I'll let the
trade play out and then I'll be looking to target
this high and then finally this high on the left
hand side. Okay, but I'm not going to be looking
to close partials at like an internal point over
here. I'm not looking to close at a specific R.
That's something I've never really understood that
to be honest with you. M a lot of people like to
say, I'll take a partial at 1:3 or 1:5. I always
ask myself, why why are you analyzing the the
chart at all? If you're looking to partial at a
random um RR point, right? It's literally just a
random point in the chart. Sometimes it'll match
up with a high or a low, sometimes it won't. My
point being is it's completely random all the
time. So, if I'm analyzing the chart, analyzing
look looking to see where price headed next,
I'm going to be targeting these areas. Yeah,
that's the whole point of analyzing the chart
in the first place in my opinion. Of course,
everybody's different, but that's just how I
view it. No, I love that. Is there anything we go
pros and cons you think that we need to cover? I
think we've Yeah, we've covered some cons. So,
we'll do pros and cons then on the strategy cuz
I'm excited to get into the charts on this one.
Um, when we say cons, as always, it's not this
is bad. It's more so that this is something to be
mindful of, something that could be a challenge,
something that could be a hurdle. Uh, it could be
bad as well. I don't know. For sure. But in terms
of cons, I would say is something you have to get
used to, right? So, it's not really a con. Again,
it's more so like something you need to be aware
of. It's something like you have to train your
eyes. Yeah, it's different. It's different for a
lot of people. Um, it's not really, to be honest
with you, I don't really see a lot of people in
the industry trading how I trade. And not to toot
my own horn, but it's just it's just a different
way of viewing the market. Um, you have to get
used to it. Kind of like an unlearn to relearn
kind of thing. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I think chart
time I think if you're not careful and this isn't
really the strategy it's more trader so something
to be aware of is you require a lot of patience
I agree you know and you have to control yourself
which I guess is every strategy uh but we'll add
it here anyway just cuz it's easy to sort of plan
your trade out start to move without you and so
on like you have to have control of yourself again
I would say that's for every strategy know
so it's not really specific to this one but
I think the patience one is very important as you
mentioned Like unless that high or low gets taken,
you're not really doing anything. Exactly.
And I think in the early days, no doubt,
it's easy to kind of do something. Um would you
say it's important to when using the strategy,
it's not necessary, but it's probably helpful
to use multiple assets. Um I always recommend
for the traders in the learning stages, I
I I would cap myself out at about two three
pairs on my watch list to be honest with you. Um
even with this system, how I trade, you're still
going to find plenty of opportunity on a weekly
basis. Uh exactly. Yeah, it was more so just so
that if let's say for any reason one has moved and
hasn't really it's very far away from a liquidity
for example, at least you have other options. But
it's good to know that it works on other assets.
So that's that can be on the pros side for sure
in terms of uh fractal in terms of very clear
understanding of what's going on in the market. Um
do you want to do that side? Yeah, let's do that.
So you have like the fractal nature of the of
the strategy and the model. You
have a very clear understanding.
So fractal nature. Yeah.
Clear understanding. Yeah.
Very very clear simple rules is what I'd say.
Yeah. Um yeah, this is again an important part
especially for this strategy is understanding
you need to have um proper rules in
place. So like you mentioned before
um I won't be buying unless these lows are
taken. I won't be selling until these highs
are taken period right no if ends or buts. So we
can write clear understanding uh strict rules.
What else we got for pros? That's strict rules.
Oh simple for sure. simplicity I would say. So
it's interesting simple though because yes it is
very simple. Yeah it's one concept essentially and
uh it's essentially drawing lines on the chart
right to mark out those liquidity highs and lows.
However, as we talked about it's complex in a way
because it's not even complex. I don't know what
the right terminology would be. You're essentially
stripping back everything you've learned.
uh things like you know your breaker structures
and so on because that's gonna work against you
when looking purely yeah and like we spoke about
earlier in the video it's like you need to almost
have a a decent understanding of these retail
concepts cuz I'm I'm almost I need to understand
them because they aid me in understanding
where the liquidity is right so yes unlearn
to relearn but you have to understand that this
you're trading two different ways you're letting
retail trade and then literally once they get
trapped that's when you're taking advantage have
you seen anyone use these concepts while still
sort of implementing other other ones or have you
found that really to use them wisely and properly
and effectively, you really just have to kind of
go all in with just focusing on liquidity. Um the
foundation of it um I've seen a lot of people use
or even people I've taught and trained in the
past use the foundation of it. And of course,
everyone will maybe have their own spin on it.
Maybe there's a specific pattern or entry model
they'll they'll use um or they'll manage their
trade differently than me. I I usually teach that
I like to hold to targets, but again, everybody's
different, right? So, some people may partial
earlier than me course, but I think I believe the
foundation is is there still. That's the important
part. Yeah, we're good. Perfect. Let's uh let's
pull out the charts. I'm excited for this. Yes,
sir. Let's take a break for a minute there,
guys, cuz I want to tell you about the best
CFD prop firm in the entire industry, Funded Next.
Funded Next is a proud sponsor of Chart Fanatics,
and they have been leading the CFD prop firm
industry for many years. is literally a top
three prop firm. Now, why is that? Let me quickly
just run through all the incredible things that
they do. First off, they have challenges for
every trader. Whatever you're looking for,
they have. They have a one-step challenge.
They have two-step challenges. And now,
industry-leading instant funding. You get
on demand payouts. You get instant access
to funding. You get a no daily loss limit.
And for every 10% you make on the account,
it doubles your account size. Mind-blowing.
absolutely crazy. Now let me tell you though
the trading conditions they are the best in
the market when it comes to raw spreads and
there are no slippage when it comes to trading
platforms they have MetaTrader 4, MetaTrader 5
and C trader as well. Something unique to Funded
Next is that on every challenge type you can get
once you've achieved 10% on your funded account
up to 15% of the profits during the challenge
phase given back to you. In addition to that,
you can also get a reward bonus equivalent to
the same amount as your subscription fee on your
first payout. And just in case that's not enough,
there's no time limit on most challenges. News
trading is allowed. There's no imposed limits
on instruments or position sizes. They have
scale up plans that can 10x your account size.
And something that they did first, if you don't
receive your payout within 24 hours, you will
receive an additional $1,000 compensation. Now,
if that doesn't tell you that they're for traders,
I don't know what will. Now, make sure you use the
code CF to get the best offer available at Funded
Next right now. The link is in the description
below. Make sure you join Funded Next today. Now,
let's get back to the episode. So, we have the
chart out. Now, we're going to go over some
trade examples of the exact strategy that we just
went over there on the whiteboard. I'm excited,
you know, I'm really excited for this. Um, it
was clear on the whiteboard. Drop a comment what
your you think so far. Is it clear? Is there
any questions you have? Uh, drop them in the
comments. Make sure you hit subscribe as always.
U, but let's get into this straight away. So,
what we have we have uh we have futures up
here, right? Yeah. So, this is the futures uh
futures market. This is the Dow Jones. So, YM uh a
beautiful sell opportunity. This was quite recent,
honestly. I think it was last week or the week
before. Um, but this is going to be an example
of a pitch perfect sell scenario I like to look
at. Um, but yeah, we are on the we'll go to the 30
minute here to start off and just to identify I'll
zoom out. You guys can get an idea of where we are
right now. This is going to be the area we want to
be focusing on. Okay. So, if we want to just have
a clear and precise marker right now, we can mark
on right away that we have a level of equal lows,
relative equal lows. Um, nonetheless, very
simple stuff. It's an area of liquidity, okay,
which tells me I want to be looking for sells into
here. Not, it doesn't mean these lows are going to
get taken right away, but it's an area to look for
if I am scoping out a sell scenario, right? Um,
so simply marked out these lows, drag it out
to the right hand side. Perfect. Now, if I zoom
into current price action, again, this is where
we're going to be looking at. This trade occurred
in the heart of New York session. So, this is
about an hour and a halfish after the open. So,
I'm always trading with New York time. So, stock
open is 9:30 a.m. for me. Um, but yeah, perfect.
So, on the 30 minute, we're going to hop into the
fiveminute chart. This is usually the time frame
I'm hanging out on. Um, kind of a do it all time
a time time frame for me to be honest. Cool. So,
zoom into current PA here and cool. We'll start
identifying and marking out everything. So,
as we know, stock open is 9:30, which is
right here. That was not what I wanted to do.
All right. So, stock open is right here at 9:30
a.m. I typically I just want to mark this on
because I understand this is a um important level
of time. Okay. Especially for the futures market.
This is when stock uh stocks open up and it has a
direct correlation with the indexes. So, I have my
marked on. Typically, I'm looking for entries
after the open. So, as you can see before the
open, this was in London. We had this bullish move
to the upside. Okay. So, if I can mark this out,
you can see how we stabbed out previous lows here.
Okay. From there, we've went bullish. All right.
Now, what can I notice and identify is we have
taken out this high. So, why is that important
for me? This is now going to be an area I'm going
to be looking at as a trap. Why? Because if retail
is looking to take this thing long, they have
now seen a BOS here. So, we can mark that on.
They want to be looked to take longs in around
this red box just like we were talking about on
the whiteboard. Right. So, we get this bullish
move up. You can see how we've spiked out all of
Asia liquidity. Yeah. Nice. That's Asia. Is that
the Asia? Yes, exactly. So, this is Asia high and
Asia low. Just the purple box just to make it nice
and clear and easy. So, again, we get this bullish
move to the upside. So, something I want to point
out here. It's what we talked about before. We
have spiked out this low, right? and ran bullish
telling me there shouldn't be any liquidity below
this low right now. So this reaction that we're
going to go and talk about soon is possible. Why?
Again we have spiked liquidity. There shouldn't
be any liquidity below this loan low right now.
So again this bullish move occurs with upside B
induces buyers spiked out Asia liquidity. Perfect.
Look how at the very top of the swing point here,
we have spiked out a high, which now tells me
there shouldn't be any liquidity above
this high. Perfect. Now, from there,
we sell off to the downside. Now, look
how we kind of chop around. This usually
happens right before New York open,
okay? It's kind of building liquidity
for New York to deal with in the future.
So, we chop around for a bit. We leave
these equal highs. Okay. Um structural
point, however you want to call it. Again,
we can simplify it as much as possible. You can
see how price has stabbed out the low we've just
marked out. Mhm. Return back to the high. So, this
is going to be an area sellers are looking to take
entries from, right? Just like we spoke about
before, high respects high. And then we sell off
to the downside. Perfect. From there, we respected
the low. Why? This is because buyers were induced
once we had this BOS in the market. So they're
looking to take entries down here. This this
is all happening again. Look at the time. This
is right after stock open. So stock opens up,
sell off to the downside. Buyers are entering
positions here. So again, we get that move away,
which is what I want to see. Okay, I want to see
this area respected and I want to see the move
away occur, which now tells me we have liquidity
below this low. Now I can look to target this.
Right, perfect. Now, if I drag this high, move
it across. Look what happens here. This bullish
move that occurs from the lows came up to sweep
these internal highs that we built right before
New York open. And it's a big surprise. We respect
this high. Why? There was no liquidity above this
high. So, of course, now since we've respected
it, there's going to be liquidity up here now.
Okay. But in this time in live price, we've spiked
out these internal highs. This is exactly this is
where I'm looking to take my sell entry there.
Right there. And again, where I'm going to be
targeting, simple stuff, liquidity, right? We've
engineered liquidity at the lows. That's where
I'm going to be targeting. So, what do you do in
terms of execution there? Are you looking to just
have a sort of a limit or stop order at that
sort of level? So, then so stop loss above the
high overall to a low. Yeah. So, I personally
don't use limits too much. I just I like to
market execute. It's just what I'm comfortable
with. Um, to be honest with you, futures you can
uh obviously with no spread and stuff. So, you
can set your limits anywhere and you'll get
filled wherever you set them. I came from a forex
background, transitioned into futures. So forex,
you have spread limits don't get tagged sometimes.
So I always wanted to avoid that. Yeah. So it's
just something that stuck with me. I just market
execute. So in this example here, just how I draw
the sell tool on, I'll have my entry. I'll
take it as soon as the high is spiked out,
just like this. Okay, got you. Okay. And again,
you can close out full here. You can partial but
don't forget about the higher time frame which
basically gave us our bias in the in the first
uh in the beginning of the video. This is going to
be my overall target right um how I would manage
this accordingly would mean I would partial here.
Y okay usually 50% maybe 70% if I'm very confident
in the higher time frame and then I'd hold the
rest of the position to the further target of
course. Um, but again, just like I was speaking
about on the on the whiteboard, I'm not the type
of person to close out partials like at this low
or at this low. No, the whole the whole reason
this whole picture in front of us right here is
these lows. These lows are telling me um buyers
have entered positions down here. So, I want to
be targeting that liquidity. Right. Exactly. So,
like you know, it's almost suffocating your trade.
I think that's the common trait of someone who's
probably not trading a plan or has gone off plan
when they are getting into the right trade but
then cutting it too early out here as I mentioned
and I think partially it could come into what we
talked about earlier which is you mark out this
low but then you see price do this explosive move
you then see come back and you think oh I need to
go long here so they get in long they go higher
they may even close out the long here look to
go short but and they still think it's long,
so they start cutting that short ASAP versus the
actual trade being, as you said, patience being
necessary. Funny thing is, patience is really if
you decided to come to your chart super early,
uh, or trade London and, uh, Frankfurt session,
let's say, when it's not part of your plan,
let's say, when if you focus on your timing,
as you said, like, you know, here's your New
York open. Yep. You know, you're really looking at
what's happening thereafter. Mhm. Then you won't
have to worry about all this mess and you won't
have to worry probably about conflicting biases
at that point because I think a large part of the
problem that people have is the fact that they sit
and wait at the chart. I know it's happened to me
so many times. Y so therefore you start looking
for what's happening now versus you might have
actually just created a nice bias on the Sunday
or you know for the day before for the next day
you know where you've objectively done it. you've
got taken your time and you've actually made a a
good bias, but then you've sat there for the next,
you know, the next morning for four or five
hours watching the 5minute chart and you've
convinced yourself. That's where a lot of people
screw up in my opinion. Um, for myself, what's
helped me a lot is I have a specific time window,
a specific time of the day I like to trade. Um,
and this is very overlooked in my opinion, but
I have a specific time window and I trade only
that. What you people need to understand is
what happens outside of the time window is
completely irrelevant to me. It doesn't bother
me. Sure, I can wake up in the morning be like,
"Ah, London had a nice move." It doesn't matter
though, right? That's not my time window. It's
not in my plan. It's not in my rules. So, why why
do I have a why do I have to care about that? I
care what's happening in my session, right? In my
timing window. This is a phenomenal trade though,
you know, even just to the low there. Beautiful.
This is very textbook, honestly. 3.6 in terms of
risk-to-reward, which is really great.
And that's a slightly higher, you know,
uh, stop loss potentially because of that wick up
to the left. But regardless, 3 to 3 uh, 1 to 3.6,
six, sorry, just to the low, let alone to
your higher time frame target that does
come through with a 1 to 10. And it's not even
about the riskreward as you mentioned earlier.
It's more so about the model you so about the, you
know, understanding of liquidity. And this really
showcases not only your lower time frame in terms
of execution and target and what's happening,
but then also why that higher time frame targeting
makes sense. very important because what happens I
don't know I don't know if this was part of the
plan but like what happened next you because we
actually had one more day before we hit the
the target is there anything that's you know
pops out to you for your model maybe it doesn't
for your model that that makes sense for that
move very simple stuff for me here is I've I've
understood I've viewed this as liquidity right
I've identified this level as liquidity these
equal lows here um and you can see how price has
respected it here okay but I understand that
if there's going to be reactions most likely
going to be false. Okay. And again, that's per my
system, right? Um, you can see once we respect it,
any buyers looking to take positions here, look
what happens here. They get another BOS in the
market. Okay. So, where will they look to take
entries from, any pullback traders maybe down
here at these levels down here or they have the
extreme look, there's imbalances down here. So,
both these red boxes I'm viewing as a trap.
This move, this move from A to B, low to high,
Yeah. has just been has been occurred to induce
buyers. Right now we have even more liquidity
below this low and overall below these lows as
well. Amazing. Yeah. Nice and simple. Honestly,
this is this is a textbook trade for sure. No,
phenomenal. Honestly, you know, I always whenever
I've this is the reason why I wanted you to to
come on to Chart Fanatics for this very reason
simply because you know I I watched you develop
this strategy over a long period of time just
putting in the chart hours. you know, most of all
and ever since then really have such a deep level
understanding of charts that you could pull up at
any chart and just start to mark out here's where
our liquidity is. It's not even about trading.
That's the thing. It's not about trading every
chart. It's just about being able to actually
identify as you said at the very very beginning
direction. Yeah. You know, once you have that
direction down, even if you don't manage to get
into a trade, it's only in eventuality that you
will eventually get into a trade. Let's say you,
you know, don't know how to execute for 6 months.
If you have the direction down, you're going to
make money eventually. Yeah, that's something.
And maybe people view my my strategy as kind of
like too precise, which is which is normal in the
beginning parts because yes, it is very precise,
but something I teach to my own um students as
well is you don't need the very top to catch that
sell. You don't need the very bottom to catch
that buy. Right. Um, like you were just talking
about the direction and the bias is the most
important part. That's what pays the profits,
right? At the end of the day, if you pull up your
phone, your MetaTrader, whatever you use to trade,
and you see the red and blue numbers, it doesn't
show you your entry, right? Metatrader doesn't
care about how pretty your entry is. If you caught
the very top or the very bottom, profit is profit,
loss is loss. There was a little phase a few
years ago, wasn't there? It was like everyone
was trying to get sniper entry. For sure. And
there's always another concept coming out,
right? Yeah. Yeah. I'm waiting for the next one.
Oh, yeah. This will be it. It's going to be around
the corner. Yeah. This will be it. position. Don't
leave. Why don't we uh I know you have two more
examples already to to go over, but why don't we
just quickly if possible just look at that EU?
It wasn't really not from a trading perspective
necessarily, but more so just like I remember our
conversation and I remember you say I remember
when you said it to me, remember my reply was
like that makes sense. I don't want it to be true
because it goes against what I said, you know. I
believe it worked out. It was right there. I know
exactly what you're talking about. So just like
you were talking a higher time frame quickly just
like daily weekly just to showcase what we were
talking about with the large move here. So it's
this large move here to the left that happened in
March. Um so it was right here from exactly yeah
low to high. So at that point you most people a
lot of people missed I know a couple people who
were positioned well before that. Um this was a
plan that was my original plan was for the long I
just uh was like going between challenge accounts
at the time etc. Um but regardless it played out
phenomenal. Now, what's annoying though for me
and I'm sure loads of people out there where they
were planning the long uh and yet we were ranging
for months like you good four or five months there
down here. Um and overall this whole long thesis
for me anyway was from a weekly monthly range u
of years right so we're at the low of that range
um and therefore looking to go back to the high
of the range or the medium whatever and that came
quite quick now over the course of what six seven
weeks now exactly yeah exactly but you know you
miss the low you get frustrated you think okay so
that's why therefore I was looking at shorts at
the highs there um to just to get to the 50% to
then buy right to get a really good buy position
and you know there's reasons to make, you know,
make sense of it. You know, Fibonacci, let's say,
let's say 50% of the range, let's say these
order blocks/ fair value gaps at the lows there,
the previous resistance being yeah, imbalance down
here, 50% over here. So many reasons to hope that
price goes there. That's the big word. Hope that
price goes there because again, all those things,
they're great tools. They're great strategies.
They work. However, the one thing I've always
loved about the liquidity aspect is that it tells
you it's a lot clearer, right? We can't sit there
and say there's 100% orders there from a CFD
perspective on futures. Yeah, we could actually go
and look at the tape and and level two data, etc.
And you probably find that they they are there,
right? That's why we're seeing the reactions.
What I'm getting at though is it allows you
to tell a story. There's more of a why behind it,
but like you said, nothing's 100%. And that's not
what I'm trying to teach or preach here, right?
Nothing's 100%. But this kind of gives me more of
a confident why to these uh these moves that occur
which just it's more of like a peace of mind and
an almost like an enjoyment as well. Even when I'm
not in a really like a trade the YM example I just
showed you guys um many people I know caught it.
I wasn't on the chart that day. Um but even seeing
it play out like it's it's beautiful to see in
my opinion. So well let's take a look at the
go lower with this one and let's just see that
example you you marked out. um you know to me
go on the 4 hour here so I know exactly what
you're talking about right here so just like we
were talking about on the um on the whiteboard
we had this liquidity buildup occur and this
happened over the course of Thursday to so this
was about two weeks of price action okay so this
is the 4 hour so this is when things get difficult
sometimes we've had this big bullish move that we
were just talking about on the higher time frames
occur um and then for like a week and a half 10
trading trading days, we um ranged, right? And
we ranged quite heavily. And this is where people
screw up. This is where people make mistakes. It's
in this type of price action in here. Okay. Um if
you learn how to stay out of price action like
this, it'll avoid you a lot of losses, a lot
of capital preservation. Um, but I remember you
messaged me and I believe we were up here or maybe
even in here somewhere and you just asked me what
I think about Euro and I said, "I don't know where
it could be going in this current moment in here,
but if I was looking to take buys, it would only
be below here." Mhm. Right. And that makes my life
so easy because even if we didn't take out this
low, it's not a move my system would have allowed
me to be in. Okay. For the most part, these lows
do go. Um, but again, nothing's ever 100%. The
simplicity be simplicity about this example is
if these lows went if they got ran cool there's
now a buy opportunity in front of us. Why was that
though? Why was that low in particular? Why not
the low down there? Why not further down? Yeah,
cuz that was the big reasoning right in terms of
like when you said it I was like that makes sense.
This is very it's very simple here and uh we
spoke about before high taken out price gives that
pullback into this extreme level. Okay. And then
from here we go bullish to the upside. Okay. So
essentially this low has respected this low. Yes.
Okay. So there's now liquidity below these lows
and then again price takes out this high comes
back down to this low. Okay. And respects it again
and moves away. That's fine. I still understand
there's going to be liquidity below this low and
that's what I need to get taken out. Okay. You
can see how there's imbalances below. But overall
like if you keep scrolling down the next internal
low is going to be all the way down here. Yeah.
And there's a huge gap in between. Exactly. So
really it's I guess it's a combination of things,
right? It's one understanding that there's so much
momentum, bullish momentum that's taken place,
that momentum is still there cuz we haven't seen
anything drastic to pull us back down. So that
means that momentum is still there. That means
really on a higher time frame if you want to talk
about structure, it's still bullish, right? Uh
so following that same narrative now you identify
the liquidity point uh at least that's you know
immediate that really there isn't really much
below that which I think is an important point.
There wasn't much liquidity below that point to
be taken out. The only way really you're going to
get there is if you then start engineering for a
long portion of time and you're probably going to
need something that drives that sort of momentum
in. Right? Instead, you have that liquidity
point and again it doesn't mean you trade it,
right? You then look for your confirmation. So
in this case actually if we take a look just from
this time frame without going lower without
really dissecting it too much and me from my
understanding just from our session here today
I would say that you have this high that then
led to obviously a new low price came up gave a
false reaction which then on the back of the fact
that we have the bullish momentum already we've
taken out liquidity on the lows I'm then looking
for longs as well I would then look to long in
this sort of area here exactly yeah and then the
important part just like you stated before is this
high respected this high on the left hand side,
right? And then if you look right above this
price action right here, I'm circling right now
is literally just this low high low to the
downside. That's structural liquidity. And
I understand that any reactions below that, so
any reactions below this high should be false,
right? And look how price even respects it,
right? So maybe another buy opportunity down
here or down here. Then look here as well. I'm
sure there's probably some sort of news catalyst
going on along these sort of wings. This was that
Trump after I I remember that there was a news in
FOMC. I believe it was late afternoon in New
York. Um late your time, but yeah, there was
some wild spikiness. Spikiness. It's interesting
though where it's where it's positioned where
it's happened because as you can see here, you
see this wick actually went lower, which means
there was a break structure on a lower time frame.
Exactly. But see what happened first. We came up,
swept out some more liquidity to the left. Yep.
brought in buyers, took those buyers out and then
we went and then the move occurred. But we only
took the buyers out on a more internal perspective
cuz the overall perspective low to high is still
intact and then we actually go and make a new high
and no doubt even just on this price action we
can see similar before we made a new high right
um which is so interesting right it's so
interesting I love it cool little detour into EU
there I appreciate that um but I think that should
open a lot of people's eyes because I know a lot
of people even probably still now are confused
with EU's movements etc but especially then at
that point y and Especially because I experienced
it myself of oh yeah I'm looking short. I had
reasons for sure but they weren't reasons based
on like a you know a log actual logical logical
in the sense that okay these patterns and these
tools we use they make sense resistance was broken
retest support that's logical cool uh we have
Fibonacci pullback cool you know discount of
the range cool um you know all of those things
make sense but it's not based on like where
are the orders exactly right I think once you
really start to pivot you're thinking that way
It's helpful because at least even me being
wrong, I already knew but more so because of our
conversation but also I I try and think in that
way as well is I knew that okay this is probably
why this is taking place right we have a lack of
liquidity liquidity actually been swept now so it
makes sense for us to be able to have a reaction
to the upside which we then got. So yeah perfect
let's take a break for a minute there guys cuz
I want to tell you about our incredible sponsor
TradeZella. Tradzella is the number one trading
tool in the entire trading industry. Tradzella
allows you to become a more profitable trader,
allows you to make immense progress as a trader,
no matter if you're a beginner or an advanced
level trader, because it makes journaling easy.
It makes journaling something that is fun and
enjoyable and something that is interactive. So,
no matter if you're a crypto trader, no matter
if you're a futures trader, no matter if you're
a forex trader, no matter if you're a stock
trader, all you have to do is select your broker,
your platform of choice, and connect it to
Tradzella, and it will automatically sync
your trades and pull all of that data onto the
dashboard, making journaling and finding your edge
and adapting your edge so easy. In collaboration
with Tradzella and Chart Fanatic specifically,
we are actually getting the playbooks from the
episodes that we're filming with these incredible
verified traders and adding them as playbooks
onto Tradezella. So, you can actually go on
there and see the rule sets already predefined.
So, make sure you check that out as well. Now,
you can actually get 10% off your monthly
subscription using CF10 on Tradzella right now.
But more importantly, I would say CF20 for 20%
off your yearly subscription with Tradezella. The
links for Tradezella are in the description below.
So, make sure you go check them out. Use CF20,
get 20% off your yearly subscription, become
a better trader today. Now, let's get back to
the episode. What do we have next? We have a NQ.
Is it cool? So, yeah, we're going to hop into an
NQ chart. This is an example on midappril time.
So, again, this one's more recent as well. Uh,
just got to look. Okay, cool. So, this is
we'll start again on the more higher time frame
perspective 30 minute 15 minute. Do you by any
chance use a crossorrelating correlating markets?
I purely focus on I don't. So, whatever chart
is in front of me is the chart I'm trading. So,
I I believe I've never really looked into it, but
there's a smart money or SMTS. Yeah. Divergence.
A lot of people look at stuff like that. I have
never personally used it. Um, no harm against it,
but uh it's just nothing I've really come across
that I that I enjoy too much. Literally, I I like
to keep it as simple as possible. Whatever is on
the chart in front of me is the chart I'm going to
be trading. Right. It's all I need. Exactly. So,
hopping on um NQ here, going to the 15 minutes.
So, we had a nice sell off to the downside. Right.
Looking to the left hand side, I can mark out this
is the start of an imbalance. Um if you go to
the lower time frames, which we're going to do,
all this is is going to be an internal low point.
Okay? And then you have that massive inefficiency
right below. Uh, cool. So, going to the
five-minute chart here. Perfect. So, just like I
was talking about here, you can see how these are
just literally all internal highs or sorry, these
are all internal lows left. Okay. Um, and all the
way down here, literally same thing over and over,
it is just structural liquidity left. Mhm. Okay.
On a maybe on a lower time frame, that's fine. But
to keep it as simple as possible, this is all
structural liquidity. And then again, you have
this whole inefficiency down below. Okay. Um, now
going to more current price action, we'll mark out
the stock open price or stock open time just to
keep everything as simple as possible. Perfect. So
this all happened in London. So in London, we
printed this low. Okay. And if you look right
above, we've left these internal highs. So the
market ends up running for it um right before
New York open here. Okay. Um and in in current
PA, we've swapped that high. Okay. Like we were
talking about before, why is this important? I'm
now viewing this high as a level that does not
have liquidity. Okay. So that's going to be of
importance later on. Perfect. You can see from
here we sold off. Okay. Look to the left hand
side. Lots of internal liquidity left here. All
right. And the market respects it for a little
bit. kind of chops around. Again, this is just
how we were talking about on YM before. Before New
York, you typically get this kind of price action,
especially on indexes. Um, and then we get
the sell off to the downside. Perfect. So,
just to summarize everything that's going on
right now, high taken, which tells me I do not
want to be buying unless this close taken.
This is if I'm buying this thing. Overall,
I understand that since the high is taken, buyers
are induced. So any re exactly any reactions at
the low tell me that buyers are not entering the
market and if there is a reaction it's going to be
false. Okay. And it's literally just engineering
liquidity for me to target. All right. Perfect.
Now I'm going to have to go into the one minute
here. I'm not typically on the one minute too
much. Um but nonetheless it is all the same to be
honest with you. Just more opportunity on M1 but
also more opportunity to uh get slapped up. Right.
So move this over to the left hand side. So again,
look at all this internal price action here.
Simple stuff. High taken, low respected. We
move away. So there's liquidity here. Same thing
over here. Finally, there's a little imbalance.
But overall, there's all internal liquidity points
that I eventually want to see get taken. So New
York open occurs and this spike came off the
back of news. Just like stock open, I'll never
enter before news. Of course, I want to wait for
the news to get released and I'm entering after.
Usually typically 2 minutes, 3 minutes, 4 minutes,
somewhere in that range. Um, but you can see here
8:30 a.m. New York um had some sort of red folded
news event which caused this spike up. Okay,
where did it spike to? Well, in early New York,
just before New York open, actually, we've taken
out this low. So, why is that important to me?
This is important because it's induced sellers in
the market, meaning they're going to be looking to
take sells below this high. Okay? And of course,
you have these imbalance up here, maybe anywhere
up there as well. But overall, I don't want to be
looking or and this comes back to having this
strict rule in place. I will not sell unless
unless this high is taken out. Okay. Okay. And if
you look to the left hand side, this high, right,
swept this this level of liquidity, leaving this
whole area, this is now an area I'm essentially
looking to take an entry off of, right? Um
I don't like to refine it too much. Sure,
you could look for an imbalance in these areas
here. It's unnecessary in my opinion. I will
always more bothered about this area getting taken
out. Exactly. As soon as this high is taken out,
my stop covers this high on the left hand side
with the futures side. Are you confident due to
the lack of you know spread etc and uh you know
centralization when it comes to the order books?
Are you confident in just having literally
your stop directly above that high versus
when you were trading forex before? Did you have
to give some buffer? Yeah, the thing about Forex
is you're going to have to um keep it well above
or or well below depending if you're buying or
selling, of course, because of spread because
there's different feeds. There's a little bit
of manipulation, right? Um but however, on these
charts, everyone's trading from one feed, right?
One chart. So, yes, I do keep mine literally like
a tick or two above the high because it's it's
just how my system is, right? I don't want to see
price above this high. So, that's the beauty of
the future is you're able to do that confidently
without 100%. So, again, stop covers this high
always. I don't want to get greedy and get too
low. Always above the high. Um, and again, entry
as soon as this high is taken out. So, that level
of liquidity is taken out. And simple things,
I'm targeting opposing liquidity. So, just like in
the NQ example, I'm sorry, in the YM example, you
can partial down at these lows where the buyers
are going to be getting trapped from. And then,
of course, you have further targets on the higher
time frames you can target as well. Right? So,
as you guys can probably notice now, there's
usually more of like a lower time frame target I'm
using to partial possibly. And then you'll have
your more higher time frame target you can finish
the whole trade at. Yeah. No, I love that. Nice
and simple again. Yeah, this is a great example
as well. This one is, as you say, it's a great
example, but it does show like the com complexity,
but it shows how it's not like copy and paste.
Like it's not every chart is super clean. Like the
original US30 example that seemed really, really
clean, really easy to sort of mark out spot. I
say easy um but quotations. But with this one,
still the understanding is there. But you can see,
especially early on before you started to mark
it all out, there was a bit more complexity,
you know, an understanding. And I think that's
where that chart time comes in that we talked
about. There is a level of really training your
eyes to understand the concept to identify the
identify. Yeah. And again, it's it's simple.
It's a really weird thing, right? It's a simple
concept. is one concept versus what most
people are doing where they're trying to
layer four or five different patterns and three
different concepts and two different indicators
and a fundamental news and a time versus this is
more time and liquidity and time isn't really as
the liquidity is most important like you could
trade London session if you wanted you could trade
anytime but you just find for your routine and for
your edge um to focus on this time and especially
where you're based as well like you know Canada
right cuz I know you did a stint where you were
trading London There was a time, yeah, back then
in the forex days. Yeah, I was trying to stay up
for the London uh London session and stuff, but
that was a killer, right? That's 2 2 3 a.m. in
uh in Toronto. So, I love that. That's an amazing
example as well. And you know what I love is that
again it's very it's fractal, right? And uh
this is more sort of your scalping/ day trading
depending how long you hold the trade for, but it
works. And you know, there is an element of that
window time. I actually love the window time thing
because I get the aspect of like for some people
can be a negative because they may work that time
right that optimum time. So I understand that side
but as a concept of using a specific time window I
love it because it starts to eliminate as long as
you stick to it that eliminate m where mistakes
can be made and eliminate sort of low probable
scenario overt trading any of that kind of thing.
Yeah. And a lot of the time those optimum times
you won't see a lot of chop, a lot of ranging.
While if you trade outside of those times,
which a lot of people do unfortunately, that's
where they end up just sitting in a trade that's
going sideways for like three four hours head
in. Right. Yeah. And then by the time the actual
momentum comes in, you've either doubled up your
leverage for no reason simply because you've been
chopping around or you get out of the trade and
then it actually plays out and then it plays out.
Yeah. Classic. Classic. That is a classic one.
What we got left? We got another Yeah, I got I
got another NQ example here for you guys. Um, this
again, all all recent trades to be honest. These
are all except for the first one. This uh this is
these are trades are all the ones I've taken. So,
um, again, this is going to be on NQ April 1st.
If you guys want to go back into your own charts
and look at it, that's cool. Um, but yeah, we'll
start off here on Wow. Okay, so we can identify
right away lows are taken, right? Not just any
sort of lows, but these are lows that we've been
respecting once, twice, three, four times, right?
And then we had this big bullish move up. Finally,
the sell-off comes and we've trapped anybody
looking to buy above these lows have been now
taken out of the market, right? So that right
there gives me that confluence is now I I can
start looking for that bullish move back to the
upside. Of course, not right away. I need to pair
this with liquidity always, but that right away is
is a massive confluence for me. So, hopping in on
the 5minute chart as per usual with me. Um, we'll
hop on the or so we'll mark on the stock open.
Perfect. So, this is another probably a a great
example for you guys because the delivery overall
is very clean. But low or sorry, high has been
taken here. Okay, going back to my strict rules,
my system, my plan is I will not be looking
for a buy until this low is taken out. Okay,
so from low, we'd end up trading higher, create
all this internal liquidity, trend line, however
you want to call it, it's just liquidity in my
eyes. Finally, we take out this high, inducing
buyers into the market. What do I mean by that?
They're going to be looking at this um as a boss,
okay? Market structure shift, whatever they want
to call it, that's fine. Um maybe looking for an
area to buy from there. uh maybe somewhere in
here or there's imbalances down here and then
finally at the low maybe an extreme area here.
Nonetheless, these are all areas I'm going to be
viewing as a trap. Okay, if there is a reaction,
false, shortlived. Okay, perfect. So, approaching
stock open. In this example here, I did want to
see stock open occur before taking a trade. Um and
sorry, before we continue here, we need to look to
the left hand side. So what do I have here? Again,
simple stuff. Liquidity. This price action I am
circling right here is again simple structure
just like this. So use that to your advantage.
We understand liquidity is above these highs.
So I can mark that out. Boom. And you can see
we've respected these highs here once and again
over here to the downside again. So this is just
building liquidity here at this blue line, right?
Yeah. Perfect. So approaching stock open, we get
the lows respected. So I'm going to drag over this
line. We have respected the lows to the left hand
side. This is at New York open. We've gone long.
Very, very choppy price action before stock open.
Finally, stock open occurs. Spike up. Clearing
internal liquidity. Now, why is this important?
If I open this up to the one minute chart,
this is important because yes, we have taken
liquid from the left hand side, but this also
induces buyers. So again, same concept. Mhm.
They're going to be looking to buy this thing.
So you can even see look how the market gives
them the reaction here. So anybody that bought
down here, they they get the reaction up and then
they get trapped. And all that is is just building
more and more liquidity below these lows and of
course below to the left hand side the one I want
to be buying below. Right. Perfect. So I drag
that over. You can see stock open again spike
up inducing buyers and then traps them. Okay.
Now that we're trading below all the liquidity,
this is now when I want to be looking for entries.
But how can I take an entry off this? Again, I
want to see some sort of level of liquidity taken.
And that that overall is going to be an area I'm
looking to take an entry off of. And if you look
right down here, look what happened. And I believe
this was the day before in New York. We spiked out
these lows. Okay. And never returned back, right?
What do I mean by that? Spiked it out and just
went bullish. Yeah. And this is the day before. So
this whole area here is definitely an area I can
look to see a buy from. Okay. And again, the whole
concept around this, the logic around this is
there's no liquidity below this low right now. So,
I'm able to take an entry off of it. Now, sure,
we've respected this blue box. It moved away. So,
yeah, now there's liquidity there. Perfect. That's
fine. But until it moves away, that is then a safe
place. Exactly. Because the liquidity really is
the the level that you've waited for. Exactly. And
again, just same thing. I'm taking an entry just
like this. Stop loss right below it always. And
just targeting liquidity on the other side of the
market just like that. Just that line to the left.
So the these uh internal highs that we marked on
beforehand, right? This again is simple stuff. All
this price action is on the left hand side is
the structure liquidity, right? So any sellers
that were getting in at these highs, there's
liquidity right there, right? So just like that.
And I believe in this example here, um I did take
small partial above the high cuz that was my first
target, right? I'm not again I'm not taking it at
a specific RR. These are targets I have in mind.
So target point here and the difference between
isn't isn't huge. Yes, exactly. But you know
if price was to reverse for that day or for any
reason continue lower um or at that point really
at that point would that liquidity then become
valid on the lows for the blue box for example
cuz it's led to a move away and broken a of course
again from a pattern perspective sure but you have
to remember um we always want to be pairing the
higher time frame right that direction that bias.
You want this high? Yes. If I wanted to frame
out a whole other buy scenario, for sure since
we have now taken out this high, if price came
down to the lows, I would never be buying this,
right? I'd want to see price below these lows
now, right? Yes. Yeah. Okay. So, you wouldn't buy,
let's say, if it did that, came back down, you
still waiting for this to to get taken. Exactly.
You wouldn't look to buy here then. No. Exactly.
Because the same no matter what. Exactly. Because
that high is taken out. I need to see this low
get traded below. Now would you say this is a
really good question I guess for people who are
very interested in this style no doubt would you
say though that is a problem that traders who
learn this system have early on is that they
will do everything else right but when it comes
to that scenario there they will then look to buy
yeah so and take a loss let's say if it does lose
um and then blame the system ah it's not working
and getting frustrated versus actually you've
broken a rule a key rule of the system there a lot
of people um that have come to me from like a a
smart money background. This is basically trading
against what they've been taught in the past,
right? Again, they like to see that BOS in the
market and then trade higher. So, they'll enter
positions here. So, based off their old teachings,
they would be looking at an enter position, enter
positions here. Um, but based off my system and
my teachings, I'm not taking entries in this
area, right? It needs to be below this low. So,
yes, these guys make mistakes in the beginning,
but they come to a quick realization that they
understand where they were getting trapped this
whole time, right? again cuz there's that more of
that why with this system. Um again, nothing's
100%. Cuz the beauty for you is if you've
partialed there, let's say. Yes. Right. You'll
break even then at that point. 100%. Yeah. So
even if it does come down lower and take out that
low and then you're able to execute because it
gives you a reason to. Yes. Um that's fine because
you've already taken profit. Exactly. You've then
been taken out break even for the rest and then
you're essentially just taking one level of risk.
If anything, you have a buffer now technically
for the next trade. Yeah. 100%. uh versus you
break even, cool, but then you execute a new trade
which doesn't really fit your system because yes,
you have a target still to target. Mhm. But you
don't now have liquidity that's been swept. So
therefore, regardless of whether it's a internal
or fair value gap or a lower time frame break
structure, it doesn't matter because it's not
your system. That's always important regardless
of your system, whether it's this or another one.
I think that that's where a lot of people do make
mistakes consistently because what they'll do
is they'll maybe execute the first trade fine
to the system perfect but then when it comes to
them scaling in those trades that they're scaling
in actually don't fit the rules at all. Exactly.
But they because the original one does and hasn't
maybe completed yet they believe that those still
fit. Does that make sense? Those scalers they're
trying they're almost trying to force it to their
original trade idea. Right. and they assume that
that those are fine because and if anything they
probably convince themselves that this trade will
work out because I've already been in a winning
trade in partial this is like a bonus right this
the market giving me a chance to get more which
never really happens no I mean often you have to
understand when you back up and you put all these
things into perspective you have a plan and rules
put out in the first place for a good reason and
uh if you can't follow it what's the point of
putting them together in the first place right
I love that hey guys this is normally where we
finish off the episode. But today, for the first
time ever, I asked Marco to trade live using the
exact same concepts he just broke down on the
whiteboard and showed trade examples from. So,
without further ado, let's get into the live
session that Marco did in New York session
on NASDAQ and you'll see the result for yourself.
Let's take a break for a minute there, guys, cuz I
want to tell you about our incredible partnership
with propfrader.com. Majority of you out there are
prop firm traders. You're using prop firms to
leverage your trading skills to be able to get
more capital and to be able to absolutely change
your life. So what's important to be able to find
the right challenge for you with the best firms
and most of all the best prices. That is exactly
what propertrader.com does. propertrader.coms
allows you to compare prop firms, be able to find
the best challenge suited to your trading style
and get you the exclusive best discounts in the
entire industry so that you're paying the cheapest
price possible for your prop firm challenge. So on
propertrader.com you'll be able to use filters to
be able to do that and find the exact challenge
for you. Be able to find your favorite prop firms.
Just look on screen right now. You can see futures
firms. You can see CFD firms with offers up to
50% off, which is incredible. And you can also
see Alpha Capital there with a one-step challenge
with 25% off using PFT1. And there's so many more
exclusive discounts only on propertrader.com.
It is the go-to site for all proper traders out
there. And one thing I'm really excited about that
I personally helped to organize was the giveaway
of giveaways. The seven figure giveaway just
through purchasing your challenges for the best
price through proper.com. Every single week you
will automatically be entered into an incredible
giveaway. A collaborative effort across all of
these firms on screen between 100 to 200k accounts
over seven figures. It means that one person
every single week who's made a purchase through
propertrader.com will be getting seven figures in
challenges that can completely revolutionize your
trading journey. Again, all you do is for any of
the firms on propertrader.com, use the code PFT
at checkout and you will automatically be entered
every single week. The link for propertrader.com
is in the description below. Now, let's get back
to the episode. just entered positions on NQ here.
Lowe's stabbed out post NYC. So after stock open,
we've had this move up to uh induced buyers, trap
them, and then we've hunted all of this liquidity.
Okay? And if you look at the the timing here,
this is this is pitch perfect. Look how the 4 hour
closed. So right at 10:00 a.m., the 4hour closed,
spiked it right into my area I want to take a
buy from below these lows. and I've added volume
there. Okay, these highs are of interest to me.
Okay, so I'm going to mark out this one. You have
an imbalance above also like the highs we left in
London. Okay, we have relative equals also 4hour
high. And then finally, there's also a high to the
left over here. So, couple targets on the way up,
but I am bullish on NQ right now. So, let's
see what kind of PA we get going through this.
Just because we've ran 4 low does not mean
this lower time frame low isn't off the cards
yet. This can definitely still get spiked
out before the the move starts going up.
You can see we're respecting this area at
the moment. All right. So sellers ideally
in this scenario they want to see price push
to the downside from here. Okay. Um and and
again just reach further targets on the left
hand side. Um sometimes what occurs is we'll
induce lower once more and then the move
will start occurring. That's why I got my
stop below PD PDL right now. 5m minute candle.
The air closes in 25 seconds which is this low.
First target from our average entry area right now
is about 320 ticks away. Only got five micros on
currently. So if hopefully doesn't mean it's
going to happen, but if we get some sort of
um entry on the way up, obviously I'm looking
to scale some more risk into this trade.
If not, it just flies. It's one of
those ones. It is what it is. So,
we'll have to manage accordingly here. All right.
My eyes are looking at these lows right now. Could
spike them before any bullish move occurs.
Just going to stay aware of that for now.
Lows are spiked here. Five minute low. So if I
have to the five, you can see now that 5minute
low spiked out. We have 7 minutes until the
15-minute candle closes. Could still chill
at the low for a little bit. So look now that you
can see sellers enter here, right? So what is that
telling me? Liquidity next five minute closes
up in about 45 seconds here. If we can get a
nice fiveminute close above, I will add a little
more volume. Um, not my favorite type of entry,
but uh, the risk-to-reward is there
and the timing is there for me. So,
I'm okay with adding this risk on. Basically, if
I do add, I'm basically predicting that this low
down here printed at 10:05 is the extreme. Okay,
the low of New York. And you need like a heavy
timing confluence in order to take these kind of
entries. But nothing convincing like I won't take
anything now. Not a strong close for me. And next
five minutes just closed up. So you can see here.
All right, lows have been spiked up once
more. It's completely fine. Like I said,
we can hang around down here for a bit. Wouldn't
be surprised before that extreme prints. But
look how many times we've tapped into this area
right now. So these highs are of interest right
now for me. Okay. Stabbed in once, twice, and
moved away. Liquidity above these highs here.
All right. So, timing now. 10:14. Now, we have
a 15 close in approximately 45 seconds here.
I feel like we're getting close to maybe
printing extreme soon, but I'm not in the
business to catch bottoms. Um, I'll just
let price tell me when the a bottom is in.
All right, good reaction off the lows now.
15 minute here. We just opened. So 5m minute
close happens in about 2 and a half minutes. We
are looking strong though. So good sign so far.
Ideally I do want to see some sort of lower
time frame confirmation on the way up so I
can add more volume. uh cuz I'm confident
in the direction of this move. However,
it does not mean the lower time frame
is always going to deliver us an entry.
Nothing of interest yet, honestly. Just struggling
at the high inducing sellers. That's it really. Um
but yeah, we got some slow PA currently. We'll
see how it unfolds in the next 30 45 minutes.
All right, starting to breach some highs here.
Timing wise, we've got 10:25. So 30 minute will
close up in about 5 minutesish here. 4 and a half
minutes. Same with the 15 that aligns. Um nothing
really to point out right now to be honest
with you guys. We got uh all these internal
points obviously I'm looking at. Um, I do want
to see us push through, run these internals,
obviously come for these highs as well. All
these blue lines are essentially targets on
the way up. All right. So, um, as for lower
time frames, I do want to add, however,
I don't see an area that I can add in yet.
Kind of just struggling around right now. Um,
just ran this internal here. We can mark that
out. Got this lower time frame low down here.
Could could add maybe below. We'll see what uh
we'll see what it looks like. It'll be about
because I'll be covering my stop below
here. So, it be about 90 ticks of risk.
All right, picking up some momentum right now. I
do see something on the lower time frames now. So,
now that we've taken out this high, if we can get
some sort of rally now, a little a little sell-off
to the downside, I will add below this low here
at 10:19. Okay, but we need to trade below this
low. Um, and that will be an area I can add some
more volume and 30 minute just closed. Beautiful
rejection. Uh, I'm confident enough in the setup
to roll my stop below this low we've created here.
So, I'll take some risk off the table, which is
great. Um, and yeah, let's continue to monitor
price action accordingly. We have spiked
out previous 30 minute. Um, we're getting
a little reaction right now. Lower time frames.
Again, if we can get some sort of push down,
spike below this low, could add volume, especially
now that I've covered risk on the initial entry.
All right, guys. Coming down here,
approaching this low. I'm going to
add volume below this low for sure.
We'll add another three contracts below
this low if we can trade below it.
All right, stabbing the low here. Adding a
little more volume and adjust this sell stop.
Cool. Now that we've traded below this low, I
do want to see price stay above 23142 or else
this scale in um is invalid, which is completely
fine. Uh risk is quite minimal now. I'm not going
to lie, since we did roll our initial stop, uh
let's see what kind of price action we get. Now,
if you want to frame this out going forward, since
we have taken out this low and this low where
we've now taken our entry from, this tells me now
sellers are interested. Okay. um which means they
want to see price back at these highs. Okay. And
then a push down. So if we get reactions in here,
do not be surprised. Okay. We are pushing to
the extreme now. We'll see how this plays out.
All we're getting a decent reaction right now.
We're on the M1. So, I don't want to be too uh
influenced by a single minute candle. But again,
once we trade back up into this into this high,
since we've taken out the previous and sold off,
I don't um I won't be surprised if we struggle
in here for a bit. Okay. And I like anticipating
these things and expecting it because when it does
occur or if it does occur, I was already mentally
um I was already mentally ready for it, right?
do want to see us hold here. This is like
the last resort kind of area for myself.
Um I believe even if we come down, spike
the low, we will revisit this one as well,
which will take us out of the trade. So
yeah, I do want to see us start holding,
pushing up. Um once we start trading into this
red box area, I will be more convinced of the
trade. I just want to see that rejection,
which we're starting to get right now.
kind of like my last area. Now we'll hold
up. We'll see. Highs taken maybe lows and
see that push up. Not looking too pretty,
though. I did want to see us come out of
this area a little quicker than we've uh what
we've been doing right now. It is still valid,
though. Of course, just coming down to
my confidence in the setup overall now.
All right, decent rejection coming in now. Um,
unfortunately, since we have just built up this
liquidity here, these lows, um, this is not out
of the cards now. So, there could be a pullback
into a continuation still. Um, so I'm not going
to rule that out. Stop is going to stay where it
is. I'm not convinced otherwise. I'm not going to
roll it because of out of fear or anything like
that. When the chart tells me to, I will. Just
got to stay aware of uh all outcomes right now.
Okay, approaching this trap area. I'm not
saying there's there has to be a reaction,
but there definitely can be a reaction from
this area. However, if there is short-lived,
I do want price to the upside. Okay, we we
will be taking partials above this high. Um,
as we stab above this structural point here,
could start rolling my stop little by little.
Okay, but I won't be paying myself yet because
we're only looking at uh 140 tick move. I'm
not interested in a small move like that.
All right, looks like we are getting this
pullback now out of this trap area, the red
box. My eyes are on this low here. If it wants
to come down to the extreme, it definitely can.
Okay, just what we anticipated right now.
We're getting rejections out of this area,
right? um now trading above this 1 minute high.
Yeah, just just have to wait unfortunately.
Uh price can get really sluggish in these
kind of areas sometimes. So just
got to wait. It is what it is.
All right. So look at this. All right. And this is
what we were talking about before. We anticipated
this to happen. We expected it. Right? So, yes,
it can get boring. Yes, it can get frustrating
if you allow it to. Um, but understanding where
price can slow down at and react at is important.
Okay? Especially when you're in a trade. Uh,
as we as we start trading above this high,
if we trade above the high, of course, um, I
will start covering my risk like I mentioned
before. Uh, and then after that, I do want to
start seeing some volume kick in, start uh,
running these highs on the lefth hand side and
eventually getting to some of our target areas.
This is aligned with the higher time frame,
so there could be a decent move. However,
I don't need the whole big
move. That's not my job here.
All right, we got an hourly close, hourly, 30, 15.
Everything's closing in five minutes here. Look at
that 30-minute wick. We're leaving big rejection
off the low. Okay. Again, we kind of predict that
10 a.m. was going to be that low of New York. 15
minutes coming. Next candle looking quite bullish
right now. Again, still trading at that high that
we've been uh we've been talking about. 5 minute,
same thing. We've had some consecutive
fiveminute closes to the upside. Again,
still respecting the high, but we'll see what
it looks like going forward here. Looks pretty
good. And highs are now being taken. So, I
will cover some risk for sure. Going to roll
my stop a little bit more. Now, the risk
is minimized. Like, it's it's small now,
right? We have uh 50 ticks of a stop available.
We're going to stay on the 5m minute here now.
Now that we're kind of out of this lower time
frame area, uh I do want to see volume start
kicking in for sure. Uh again partials will
be above this high which is roughly 320 ticks.
All right we've got our hourly close. Let's
take a look at this. So hourly big rejection.
Take a look at the timing again. Like we
talked about the beginning of this video
here. Spiked out previous 4hour low. Okay, in
10 a.m. SPE spiked at 9:00 a.m. and we've got
that rejection to the upside. All right, 30 minute
ended up closing bullish after that big wick. So,
we wick down on the 30 and spiked all the way
back up and closed back above um starting to
get a nice push. Finally, finally, um I will
be closing a nice part a nice partial above
this for sure above this high here we printed
at 9:35. So this is right after stock open.
Also definitely going to start uh I mean we are
roughly 200 ticks in profit currently. There is no
reason why I would want to see price back down to
my entry. That'd be foolish of me to be this much
in profit and let price come back to take me out
in the red. So stop is now rolled to be. Timing
wise is getting a little bit late. I usually don't
stay on the chart at this time. Um, so we'll see
what price looks like when we approach this high.
What timing is looking like when we approach this
high, I might close out full. I might close
out a partial. We'll have to wait and see here.
All right, we're getting a steep
pullback right now. Not ideal, but
we'll see. We'll see. This could just be um a
move inducing sellers right now. Nonetheless,
risk has been covered. No partial points has
been hit yet. All right. So there's no ifands,
buts. I had targets in mind. If it
doesn't reach it, then there's no
uh then there's no profits and it is what it is.
All right. 5 minute spiked out here. Okay. Uh
again, I'm viewing this bearish move as a pullback
right now. Hopefully it is. It could sell. Um
again, just per my my setup right now. Overall,
the higher time frames, I am viewing this as a
pullback. Okay. Um and we did spike 5 minute.
We running some sort of internals to the left.
However, this leg here is not pretty. Okay. So,
I do see downside potential. That's why
risk is risk is off the table now. It's
in the market's hands. If it wants to run to
our target, great. If not, hey man, it's a be
my lower time frame. Highs taken,
lows taken. I do want to see the
move start now. That continuation up.
Let's see. Let's go NQ.
Give us a little push here.
All right, five minute just closed up. Here's
another fiveminute low just taken. Uh timing
is getting tough now. It's 11:15. I do want to
see this move start occurring relatively soon.
Okay, looks like this pullback we've had this
bearish move to the downside looks like could
be finished. All right, we've held this low
here. Now we're showing momentum back up to
the highs. Um reason being why I view this
as a pullback was look to the left hand side,
right? We've we've done nothing, right? Like
look at this bit of price action we got here.
Um it's just a buildup of liquidity. Um this
high tapped into what? Absolutely nothing,
right? and just fuel the little sell-off in my
opinion to induce sellers. So, this area we're
tapping into right now, view it as a uh a trap as
well. Okay. Um, however, I don't believe we will
stall in here for too long, but it is an area that
uh sellers would look to take this asset lower.
All right, guys. as we start
pushing about this high. Um,
again due to timing and these is just
things you have to react to sometimes. I
will start partially in this area and then full
target will be the high that doesn't change.
All right guys, another 30-minut close here.
It is 11:30 now. Um, but again, nonetheless,
still a great close. 30-minute closing bullish
above previous high um indicating right if we're
analyzing just raw price action right now it's
just telling us we've got uh continuations on the
cards currently until something tells us otherwise
right and if we hop into the lower time frames you
can see this area that we've pointed out before
that we're still trading in um I didn't believe
we were going to stay in it for too long
um it's been about seven six seven minutes
now. Uh so I mean these are just one of those
trades where we've been struggling since entry,
right? We've been in this trade for an hour and a
half now. Um not the cleanest bit of price action
obviously coming out of that, but not every
uh not every setup's going to be rocketing to
your TP or melting to your TP. Sometimes you
just got to stick it out, manage accordingly.
um I'm not going to let these candles influence me
to close early or um manage the trade incorrectly.
Right? Sometimes all it takes is taking the
entry, setting your stop and a target. What
happens in between it's it's irrelevant. All
right? Now, I don't want to say irrelevant.
Um but don't let these candle closures influence
you and make you get emotional and stuff, right?
Definitely possible for price to run these
lows now. These lows I've just marked out.
All right. So maybe a spike below and then see
that continuation up. That's what I'm leaning
towards right now. Um looking at this from a
retail perspective, right? Anybody looking to
sell in this red box in this area, what are
they going to view this as? Right? Like a
break of structure, a change of momentum. So
they might start looking for bearish moves,
right? Automatically when that happens, this
is this induces sellers into the market,
which now tells me there's even going
to be more liquidity above this high,
right? So I'm not against price taking out this
low and then seeing that continuation. Um so
just just staying aware of that, of course, can
move from where it is now. Of course, the market
can do whatever it wants, but if it does spike
this low, it makes sense to uh continue bullish.
All right, we're approaching this high now. Man,
it's been a bit. Uh, but patience, patience,
patience. It's what about it's what it's about
sometimes in these markets, man. It's not always
going to be so so clean. But as we stab this high,
hopefully we do soon. We're leaving a little bit
of a wick right now, but as we stab this high, I
will start scaling off some volume um and paying
myself. And of course, our target remains the
same up here at 23 237.5. Um, time is getting
definitely tight now because we're approaching
uh New York lunch hour, typically the the hour
tends to be dead in volume. And um, I mean, if we
if we've been quite dead now, I can only imagine
what we're going to get through the uh through
the lunch hour. So, in an ideal situation,
we we move now and I'm out of this position
before lunch, but we'll see what happens here.
All right, high take in here.
Going to be paying myself,
taking some off um and letting this
thing run to these highs. Ideally
now I want to see this uh this momentum
coming. I mean we've been asking for it
but we've been slowly moving to targets but
just so so slowly right I mean slowed down
in this area which we expected slowed
down in this area which again which
we expected. Um it'd be nice to just see
that that continuation now that push up to
these highs. Um I do want to be out of this
before this lunch hour occurs ideally. Um,
I'll look to take off a little bit more volume
soon and then be 100% out at the high here.
All right, taking off another two
cons here. I got four cons left.
All right, guys. Another two off here.
We are so close now to target. We got,
man, 20 ticks left. It's been how long now? Uh,
we can't complain. It's been an hour and
50 minutes. But we are like 80% out of
the position now. Just need that fast that last
little uh push. We can close this remainder out.
All right, guys. Wow. high's taken. Let's close
out here. And look at that move. Wow. We've
been we've been waiting for this now for quite a
while. What a move up now. Wow. That puts us at
about 1,600 in four accounts. So 32 about six
$6,400 across four accounts. Great day of trading.
Wow. Well, Marco, I really appreciate you breaking
that down for us today. There was no gatekeeping.
I know that's a lot of uh what people think when
it comes to especially unique strategies like
this. So, I really appreciate you breaking this
down over multiple concepts as well. I'm truly
fascinated as always and you know, I've been
trying to deep dive into this sort of style of
trading for a long time. But everyone at home,
drop a comment with your biggest takeaway from
this episode. Drop a comment with any questions
you have on this style. uh because I'll make sure
Marco replies to them and checks them out. Maybe
we do a part two. But hit subscribe, hit like. Uh
links for Marco will be in the description below,
so check those out. Also, make sure you give him a
follow. We're trying to get him more on X as well,
get him involved with the trading community. So,
go check that out and hit subscribe. Other
episodes are on screen. And until next time, take